<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" >

<chapter id="installation">
    <title>Installation</title>
    
    <para>Installation and requirements details for J4Schema extension</para>
    
    <section id="requirements">
        <title>Requirements</title>
        
        <para>
            J4Schema is tested on Joomla! 2.5; however it <emphasis>should</emphasis> work on Joomla! 1.7, too. 
            Anyway, we strongly suggest you to always use the latest Joomla! version, since it patches all the known bugs.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            System requirements are less restrictive than Joomla!, so, if you can run the CMS without problems, you shouldn't have 
            any problems with this extension.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            J4Schema is integrated with <ulink url="http://www.joomlacontenteditor.net/">JCE editor</ulink>, so you need to install 
            and use it as editor for your articles.
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="download">
        <title>Download</title>

        <para>
            You can get the latest version of our extension from the "Download" section of our site. We have created a "one-click-installer" 
            package, once installed you will find:
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <simpara>FrameworkOnFramework library</simpara>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <simpara>J4Schema component</simpara>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <simpara>J4Schema JCE plugin</simpara>                  
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
      
        <note>
            <para>
                You should always use the latest version, since we constantly work on fixing bugs and adding new features.
            </para>
        </note>
    </section>

    <section id="configuration">
        <title>Configuration</title>
        
        <note>
          <para>
            On package installation, everything should be ready to use. However, if you have any problems on JCE plugin, you should check these steps.
          </para>
        </note>
        
        <para>
            If you have deleted or you're not using the <emphasis>Default</emphasis> profile, you have to manually add the J4Schema button on 
            JCE editor. To do that, you have to go in <emphasis>JCE Administration</emphasis> &#187; <emphasis>Edit profile</emphasis> &#187; 
            <emphasis>Features tab</emphasis> and drag&amp;drop the Google button.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            As last step, you have to disable the "Cleanup HTML" features, since we're adding non-standard HTML tags, JCE sees them as
            errors and strips them out from your articles.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            You can disable it from <emphasis>JCE Administration</emphasis> &#187; <emphasis>Editor Global Configuration</emphasis>.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            Excellent! You're ready to start!
        </para>
    </section>
  </chapter>