<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" >
<chapter id="pro-version">
  <title>Professional Version</title>
  
  <para>
    Inside <emphasis>J4Schema Professional</emphasis> package you'll find new features and some useful function 
    that will help you on choosing and selecting the Schema.org elements.
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <simpara><emphasis>Token management</emphasis> Automatically replace your own tokens with Schema.org attributes</simpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <simpara>
          <emphasis>Template overrides for standard tokens</emphasis> We provided template overrides for <code>com_content</code> component 
          with standard Schema.org attributes. However you can apply the same logic to every part of your site!
        </simpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <simpara>
          <emphasis>Auto-expansion of tree type</emphasis> On editor view, if the attribute you have chosen 
          could be an <code>itemtype</code>, there will be a shortcut to automatically expand the type tree to that element
        </simpara>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  
  <section id="how-to-use-pro">
    <title>How to download/install</title>

    <para>
      Professional versions are available to users with an active membership. Once you purchased it, you will find the professional packages inside 
      every version; you can install it as a regular Joomla! package.
    </para>
    
    <note>
      <title>Updates for Pro versions</title>
      <para>
        To enable automatically updates you must enter your <guilabel>Download ID</guilabel> inside the Download ID field that you can find in the 
        Option page of the component.
      </para>
    </note>
  </section>
  
  <section id="token-management">
    <title>Token management</title>
    
    <para>
      As usually let's start with an example. Let's say you have styled your article with the attributes you wanted. Everything is perfect, but you 
      want to style other parts of your site, too. 
    </para>
    <para>
      What if you want to add information on your blog layout, saying that every article is a independent element, with its category, its creation time 
      and so? Using the JCE editor plugin you can't, since your scope is limited to the article; you need another tool.
    </para>
    
    <section id="token-logic">
      <title>The logic</title>
      
      <para>To simplify things, we have introduced a search&amp;replace token system. What does it mean?</para>
      <para>
         Well, it's quite simple: you create a token and assign him a value (it could whatever you want), then you add these tokens to your site: you
         can add them inside your articles, inside your template, on your template overrides... <emphasis>wherever</emphasis> you want.
      </para>
      <para>
        Next, our system plugin will replace the token string with the value you just typed.
      </para>
      
      <para>
        For example, you can create a token named <code>ARTICLE_WRAPPER</code> and replace it with
      </para>      
      <para>
        <code>itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/WebPage"</code>
      </para>
      
      <para>
        Your starting text is something like that:
        <programlisting>
        <![CDATA[
<div { ARTICLE_WRAPPER } class="item-page<?php echo $this->pageclass_sfx?>">
...
...
</div>]]>
        </programlisting>
         
         But the final output (read from search engine) would be:
         <programlisting>
        <![CDATA[
<div itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/WebPage" 
     class="item-page<?php echo $this->pageclass_sfx?>">
...
...
</div>]]>
        </programlisting>
      </para>
      
      <para>
        This example is taken from the <emphasis>default</emphasis> layout of <emphasis>Article</emphasis> view of the 
        <emphasis>com_content</emphasis> component and it's inside the installation package.
      </para>
      <para>
        Let's see how to add and manage more token.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="install-template-overrides">
      <title>Install template overrides</title>
      
      <note>
        <title>What's a template override?</title>
        <para>
          If you don't know what's a template override, you really should read this guide: <ulink url="">Joomla! template override system</ulink>, 
          since we're going to use them a lot!
        </para>
      </note>
      
      <para>
        First of all, you should setup template overrides. Surf to the <guibutton>Template overrides</guibutton> submenu
        and you will find two tables.
      </para>
      
      <para>
        The table on the left, shows the ready-to-use overrides that come with <guilabel>J4Schema</guilabel>, on the right you can find 
        the overrides that already exist. 
      </para>
      
      <para>
        When you click on <guibutton>Copy overrides</guibutton> toolbar button, J4Schema overrides will be copied inside your current 
        template override folder; if the files are already present, they will be backed up.  
      </para>
      
      <para>
        Our overrides won't change the presentation of your articles, the are just <emphasis>com_content</emphasis> 
        layouts with inside our tokens, ready to use.
        However, if you already have your overrides (and you want to keep them), you have to manually merge ours with yours. You can find 
        our file inside this folder:
      </para>
      <para>
        <code>site_root/administrator/components/com_j4schema/overrides</code>
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="token-list">
      <title>Token list</title>
      
      <para>
        In <guilabel>J4Schema</guilabel> component, surf to the <guibutton>Tokens</guibutton> menu, you will find the default tokens inside the 
        installation package.
      </para>
      
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/token_list.jpg" scalefit="1"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
      
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>ID</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>It's the token ID</para></listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Token Name</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              It's the token name. This string (wrapped with <code>{ }</code>) will be replaced with the string inside the column <emphasis>Token replace</emphasis>
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Integration</term>
          <listitem><para>It's the type of integration, at the moment there is only Joomla</para></listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Token type</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              It's the type of the token. Available types are <emphasis>text</emphasis> or <emphasis>date</emphasis>
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Token replace</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>It's the text that will replace the <emphasis>Token name</emphasis>
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Published</term>
          <listitem><para>Is this token published?</para></listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      
      <para>
        Here you can perform all the standard actions: publish, unpublish, add, delete and modify.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="create-a-token">
      <title>Create a token</title>
      
      <para>
        When you try to add or modify a token, you'll find this view:
      </para>
      
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/token_add.gif" scalefit="1"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
      
      <para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Token name</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                It's the text that will be replaced, ie <emphasis>MY_TOKEN</emphasis>. 
                
                <note>
                  <para>
                    Please entry it on uppercase, alphabetics only, without any spaces or digits. 
                    Avoid colons (<code>:</code>), since it's reserved char, used to parse data from 
                    tokens (you'll learn more when we'll add a <emphasis>date</emphasis> token).
                  </para>
                </note>                
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Integration</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                It's the "domain" of integration; at the moment there is Joomla! only, but in the future 
                more will come (K2, Virtuemart and so on).
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Token type</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                It's the type of the token, it could be <emphasis>text</emphasis> or <emphasis>date</emphasis>. They are almost the same,
                but in the latter case you have to "style" your token in template overrides in a different way.  
              </para> 
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Published</term>
            <listitem><para>To publish/unpublish a token</para></listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Token replace</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                This is the most important field, since it holds Schema.org attributes. If you know what to add, you can add them
                manually; in the other case you can explore the type/attributes tree and then click on <guibutton>Add type</guibutton> or
                <guibutton>Add attribute</guibutton> button. 
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist> 
      </para>
      
      <note>
        <para>
          Please note that J4Schema can't verify if the data you added is correct, since you could add nested tokens.
          To ensure that everything is ok, you can use this <guilabel>Google</guilabel> tool: 
          <ulink url="http://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/richsnippets">Rich Snippets Testing Tool</ulink>
        </para>  
      </note>
      
      <para>
        Now you know everything you need to start adding tokens, let's start with an example. 
      </para>
      
      <section id="add-tokens">
        <title>Add tokens</title>
        
        <para>
          Ok, let's say we want to add some information to the article we have just created in the previous examples 
          (the one about the "Avatar" film, do you remember?).
        </para>
        
        <para>
          Here you can find the sections of the article view that we can style:
          
          <screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/token_article.gif" scalefit="1"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot>
        </para>
        
        <para>
          <orderedlist>
            <listitem><para>Article title</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Category</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Publish date (or any other date such as Creation date or Modified date)</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Related links</para></listitem>
          </orderedlist>
        </para>
       
       <para>
        So this, is a snippet of a template override for the article (some parts were removed):
        <note>
          <para>
            In these examples there is a space between the token name and <code>{</code> or <code>}</code>. We had to
            do so to prevent Joomla to parse them as plugin in these articles; inside template overrides you have to
            remove that space.
          </para>
        </note>
       </para>
        
       <example>
        <title>Article Tokens</title>
        <programlisting><![CDATA[
<div { ARTICLE_WRAPPER } class="item-page<?php echo $this->pageclass_sfx?>">
[...]
	<div { ARTICLE_BODY }>
    [...]
<?php if ($params->get('show_title')) : ?>
	<h2 { ARTICLE_TITLE }>
	<?php if ($params->get('link_titles') && !empty($this->item->readmore_link)) : ?>
		<a { ARTICLE_LINK } href ="<?php echo $this->item->readmore_link; ?>">
		<?php echo $this->escape($this->item->title); ?></a>
	<?php else : ?>
		<?php echo $this->escape($this->item->title); ?>
	<?php endif; ?>
	</h2>
<?php endif; ?>

[...]

<?php if ($params->get('show_category')) : ?>
	<dd class="category-name" { ARTICLE_CATEGORY }>
	[...]
	</dd>
<?php endif; ?>
      [...]
	</div>
</div>
]]>
        </programlisting>
       </example>

      <para>
        If you use our tokens, too, this is the HTML output:
        
        <example>
          <title>Article HTML after token replace</title>
          
          <programlisting><![CDATA[
<div class="item-page" itemtype="http://schema.org/WebPage" itemscope>
[...]
    <div itemprop="mainContentOfPage">
    [...]
        <h2 itemprop="name">
          <a href ="" itemprop="url">J4Schema</a>
        </h2>
    [...]
        <dd itemprop="genre" class="category-name">
            Category: <a href ="test-blog">Blog</a>
        </dd>
    [...]	
    </div>
</div>
]]>
          </programlisting>
        </example>
      </para>
      
      <para>
        This is only a simple example, but, as you can see, once you set up everything, it works automatically!
        Even in the worst case (token not replaced) your page style won't be affected, since your browser will ignore the tokens! 
      </para>
      
      <tip>
        <title>Can I add a token wherever I want?</title>
        <para>
          The short answer is: <emphasis>Yes, you can!</emphasis>.
        </para>
        <para>
          Here it is the longer and more techincal one. J4Schema uses a system plugin, loaded in the <code>onAfterRender</code> event.
          This event is fired just before sending the output, so we can manipulate the text however we want!
        </para>
      </tip>
      
      <para>Now let's see a particular token: the <emphasis>date token</emphasis> </para>
      </section>
      
      <section id="add-a-date-token">
        <title>Add a date token</title>
        
        <para>
          As we already said, the date token is different from the text one.
        </para>
        
        <para>
          Take a look at the <code>ARTICLE_PUBLISH_UP</code> token in the token list: it's like a regular
          one, but its type is <emphasis>date</emphasis>. 
        </para>
        
        <para>
          So far so good, ok? Now move to the template override and search for it. As you can see it's quite different
          from the other ones.
        </para>
        
        <programlisting><![CDATA[
<time { ARTICLE_PUBLISH_UP:<?php echo $this->item->publish_up?> }>
   <?php echo JText::sprintf('COM_CONTENT_PUBLISHED_DATE_ON', 
              JHtml::_('date', $this->item->publish_up, JText::_('DATE_FORMAT_LC2'))); ?>
</time>]]>
        </programlisting>
        
        <para>
          As you can see, we have to wrap the text we want to style with a <guibutton>time</guibutton> tag, then
          add the token to it.
        </para>
        
        <para>
          The token syntax is quite different, since we have to pass to the plugin the date in order to transform it
          into the ISO format. To do that we have to add a colon (<code>:</code>) after the token name, then output
          the date value.
        </para>
      </section>
    </section>

  </section>
  
  <section id="pro-congratulations">
      <title>Congratulations!</title>
      
      <para>
        Congratulations! Now you should know everything you need to start adding Schema.org attributes to your site.
      </para>
      
      <para>So what's next?</para>
      <para>
        We suggest you to take a look and become familiar with Schema.org syntax and its use;
        we gave you the tools but you have to add your own knownledge :)</para>
      
      <para>
        Here you can find a list of usefull links:
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem><simpara><ulink url="http://schema.org">Schema.org homepage</ulink></simpara></listitem>
          <listitem><simpara><ulink url="http://schema.org/docs/gs.html">Schema.org tutorial</ulink></simpara></listitem>
          <listitem><simpara><ulink url="http://schema.org/docs/full.html">Schema.org full reference</ulink></simpara></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
      
    </section>
</chapter>