<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" >
<chapter id="pro-version">
  <title>Professional Version</title>
  
  <para>
    Inside <emphasis>J4Schema Professional</emphasis> package you'll find new features and some useful function 
    that will help you on choosing and selecting the Schema.org elements.
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <simpara><emphasis>Token management</emphasis> Automatically replace your own tokens with Schema.org attributes</simpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <simpara>
          <emphasis>Template overrides for standard tokens</emphasis> We provided template overrides for <code>com_content</code> component 
          with standard Schema.org attributes. However you can apply the same logic to every part of your site!
        </simpara>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <simpara>
          <emphasis>Auto-expansion of tree type</emphasis> On editor view, if the attribute you have chosen 
          could be an <code>itemtype</code>, there will be a shortcut to automatically expand the type tree to that element
        </simpara>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  
  <section id="how-to-use-pro">
    <title>How to download/install</title>

    <para>
      Professional versions are available to users with an active membership. Once you purchased it, you will find the professional packages inside 
      every version; you can install it as a regular Joomla! package.
    </para>
    
    <note>
      <title>Updates for Pro versions</title>
      <para>
        To enable automatically updates you must enter your <guilabel>Download ID</guilabel> inside the Download ID field that you can find in the 
        Option page of the component.
      </para>
    </note>
  </section>
  
  <section id="token-management">
    <title>Token management</title>
    
    <para>
      As usually let's start with an example. Let's say you have styled your article with the attributes you wanted. Everything is perfect, but you 
      want to style other parts of your site, too. 
    </para>
    <para>
      What if you want to add information on your blog layout, saying that every article is a independent element, with its category, its creation time 
      and so? Using the JCE editor plugin you can't, since your scope is limited to the article; you need another tool.
    </para>
    
    <section id="token-logic">
      <title>The logic</title>
      
      <para>To simplify things, we have introduced a search&amp;replace token system. What does it mean?</para>
      <para>
         Well, it's quite simple: you create a token and assign him a value (it could whatever you want), then you add these tokens to your site: you
         can add them inside your articles, inside your template, on your template overrides... <emphasis>wherever</emphasis> you want.
      </para>
      <para>
        Next, our system plugin will replace the token string with the value you just typed.
      </para>
      
      <para>
        For example, you can create a token named <code>ARTICLE_WRAPPER</code> and replace it with
      </para>      
      <para>
        <code>itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/WebPage"</code>
      </para>
      
      <para>
        Your starting text is something like that:
        <programlisting>
        <![CDATA[
<div { ARTICLE_WRAPPER } class="item-page<?php echo $this->pageclass_sfx?>">
...
...
</div>]]>
        </programlisting>
         
         But the final output (read from search engine) would be:
         <programlisting>
        <![CDATA[
<div itemscope itemtype="http://schema.org/WebPage" 
     class="item-page<?php echo $this->pageclass_sfx?>">
...
...
</div>]]>
        </programlisting>
      </para>
      
      <para>
        This example is taken from the <emphasis>default</emphasis> layout of <emphasis>Article</emphasis> view of the 
        <emphasis>com_content</emphasis> component and it's inside the installation package.
      </para>
      <para>
        Let's see how to add and manage more token.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="create-a-token">
      <title>Create a new token</title>
      
      <para>
        xx
      </para>
    </section>
    
  </section>
</chapter>