<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook V5.0//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/docbook.dtd" >

<chapter xml:id="installation">
    <title>Installation</title>
    
    <para>Installation and requirements details for J4Schema extension</para>
    
    <section xml:id="requirements">
        <title>Requirements</title>
        
        <para>
            J4Schema runs on both Joomla! 1.7 and Joomla! 2.5 . We strongly suggest you to always use the latest Joomla! version, since
            it patches all the known bugs.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            System requirements are less restrictive than Joomla!, so, if you can run the CMS without problems, you shouldn't have 
            any problems with this extension.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            J4Schema is integrated with <ulink url="http://www.joomlacontenteditor.net/">JCE editor</ulink>, so you need to install 
            and use it as editor for your articles.
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="download">
        <title>Download</title>

        <para>
            You can get the latest version of our extension from the "Download" section of our site. J4Schema package consists in 3 files:
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <simpara>J4Schema component <emphasis>(com_j4schema.zip)</emphasis></simpara>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <simpara>J4Schema cleanup plugin <emphasis>(plg_j4schema_cleanup.zip)</emphasis></simpara>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <simpara>J4Schema JCE plugin <emphasis>(JCE_plg_j4schema.zip)</emphasis></simpara>                  
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
      
        <note>
            <para>
                You should always use the latest version, since we constantly work on fixing bugs and adding new features.
            </para>
        </note>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="installation-steps">
        <title>Installation</title>
        
        <para>
            J4Schema component and cleanup plugin are standard Joomla! extensions, so you can install them as usual with the <emphasis>
            Joomla! Extension manager</emphasis>. J4Schema JCE plugin is a JCE extension, so you have to install it from its control panel.
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section xml:id="configuration">
        <title>Configuration</title>
        
        <para>
            First of all you need to enabled the content plugin <emphasis>J4Schema cleanup</emphasis>, otherwise microdata attributes
            will not display correctly.
            
            <tip>                   
                <para>
                    You have to install this plugin since we're adding some non-standard HTML attributes and, sometimes, JCE editor won't
                    process them in the right way.
                </para>
                <para>
                    For example, when you add the <code>itemscope</code> attribute, JCE will process it as it would be a standard attribute,
                    adding <code>=""</code>. So, you will have this wrong text: <code>itemscope=""</code>.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Schema.org dictionary, instead, wants it without any quotes, so we have to manipulate it and eliminate them.
                </para>
            </tip>
        </para>
        
        <para>
            After that, you have to add the J4Schema button on JCE editor. To do that, you have to go in <emphasis>JCE Administration</emphasis> &#187; 
            <emphasis>Edit profile</emphasis> &#187; <emphasis>Features tab</emphasis> and drag&amp;drop the Google button.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            As last step, you have to disable the "Cleanup HTML" features, since we're adding non-standard HTML tags, JCE sees them as
            errors and strips them out from your articles.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            You can disable it from <emphasis>JCE Administration</emphasis> &#187; <emphasis>Editor Global Configuration</emphasis>.
        </para>
        
        <para>
            Excellent! You're ready to start!
        </para>
    </section>
  </chapter>